

Tuomo **Kareoja**

DATA SCIENTIST · DATA ENGINEER

Müllerstraße 130, 13349 Berlin, Germany

□ (+358) 050 3740592 | ■ tuomo.kareoja@gmail.com | □ TuomoKareoja | 面 tuomo-kareoja

Summary and Skills

I'm a data scientist/engineer specialized in relational databases, data pipelines and interactive dashboards. Domain knowledge in hospital management analysis and used cars market. Board games and piano for free time.

Programming Python, R, bash, LaTeX

BI Tools Microsoft Power BI, Tableau

Statistical Software RStudio, SPSS, SAS, RapidMiner

Databases Posgresql, Microsoft SQL Server

DevOps Docker

Languages Finnish, English, German (basic), Swedish (basic)

Experience

Nordic Healthcare Group

Finland

DATA SCIENTIST Feb. 2019 - Present

• Database design and testing and planning of data pipelines

• Champion for version control and project management tools

Nordic Healthcare Group Finland

 Data Analyst
 Jan. 2017 - Feb. 2019

• Database management, statistical inference and model building, interactive visualization and discrete event simulations

Grey-Hen Oy Finland

JUNIOR DATA ANALYST Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- Quality control of the automated data gathering and report generation. Documentation of the process chain and datasets
- · Paternity leave replacement

University of Helsinki Finland

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Jan. 2012 - Dec. 2016

• TA in numerous statistical courses at the departments of social psychology and statistics

Education

Ubiqum Berlin, Germany

Data Science Bootcamp

July 2019 - December 2019

- On-site fulltime 5 month project based training course
- Technologies used: Python, R, MySQL, Spark, AWS, Docker
- Algorithms used: GLM, KNN, RF, SVM, GBM, apriori, SARIMAX, Prophet...

University of Helsinki Helsinki, Finland

B.S. IN STATISTICS 2012 - 2019

- · Ongoing studies for a second major.
- Weighted grade average: 4.53 (scale 0-5)

University of Helsinki Helsinki, Finland

M.Soc.Sc. in Social Psychology 2012 - 2015

- Masters weighted grade average: 4.91 (scale 0-5), Master's thesis: Eximia
- Bachelor weighted grade average: 4.02 (scale 0-5)